<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode type="Other" icon="./extTool16x16.gif">
	<name>External Tool</name>
	<shortDescription>
		 Executes an external tool.
	</shortDescription>
	
	<fullDescription>
	<intro>Allows running an external program on the data. It will write out 
	the incoming datatable into a temporary file which can be used as an input to
	an external tool. After the tool finishes the node will read in an output
	file the tool has (hopefully) created.<br />
	NOTE: Running an external executable takes the control out of our hands. 
	There will be no progress, no failure message, exceptions will not be caught,
	it may even cause the entire KNIME platform to fail and you loose any unsaved
	data, etc. Especially, if a shell script (or .bat file) creates sub processes (by
	calling other programs), these sub processes will continue living even if 
	the node gets canceled. Furthermore, their output will not be fetched,
	causing them (possibly) to block (not finishing their job) and to exist 
	until you kill them off manually.<br />
	Highlighting will not work across this node. 
	Colors are lost (the Color Manager node must be
	inserted in the flow to re-generate colors). <br />
	The output of the external tool is caught and can be seen
	in the node's views (the last 500 lines only, full output
	is logged to KNIME's log file - if the log level is set to DEBUG, which is the
	default).
    </intro>
    <option name="Input Data File">Enter a file path and name. Before calling the
        external tool the data from the input port will be written into this file - 
        with the column separator specified and with or without column names and row 
        IDs, depending on the corresponding checkmarks.
	</option>		
    <option name="External Tool">Specify an existing and executable file that 
    will be called with the specified command line arguments. Before executing 
    this external tool, the current working directory is set to the specified
    directory. The input file is NOT automatically transfered into the external
    tool. You need to specify appropriate command line arguments to read this
    file with your external tool. The tool also needs to write its output into
    the specified location, in order for the node to pick it up from there.
	</option>		
    <option name="Output Data File">Specify the file that is created by the
    external tool with its output data. The node reads the content of this file
    and provides it at its output port. Also specify the separation character
    used in the file and if the file contains column names and row IDs.
	</option>		
	</fullDescription>
	
	<ports>
		<dataIn index="0" name="External Input">Input data for the external tool</dataIn>
		<dataOut index="0" name="External Output">Data read from the output file of the tool</dataOut>
	</ports>	
	<views>
		<view index="0" name="Tool output">
			The text sent to standard out during the execution of the external tool.
			(If it appears in gray, it's the output of a previously failing run
			which is preserved for your trouble shooting.)<br />
			NOTE: Keeping the view open may slow down the process significantly,
			if it produces a lot of output in a short amount of time.
	    </view>
		<view index="1" name="Tool error output">
			The text sent to standard error output during the execution of the external tool.
			(If it appears in gray, it's the output of a previously failing run
			which is preserved for your trouble shooting.)
	    </view>
	</views>
</knimeNode>