<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode type="Other" icon="./extSSHTool16x16.png">
    <name>External SSH Tool</name>
    <shortDescription>
         Executes an external tool on a remote machine via SSH.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
    <intro>Allows running an external program on another machine on the input data.
    The node creates an SSH connection to a remote host, transfers the input data
    via sftp (as comma separated values), executes the specified command and transfers
    back the result file, assuming that the command generated a file with comma separated values.
    <br />
    NOTE: KNIME has no control over the execution of the external tool. 
    There will be no progress, no failure message, and exceptions will not be caught. 
    Highlighting will not work across this node. 
    Colors are lost (the Color Manager node must be
    inserted in the flow to re-generate colors). <br />
    For additional SSH settings, please refer to the preference page 
    "General" - "Network Connections" - "SSH2". There the directory with the
    known_hosts file and the private key file can be specified.
    </intro>
    <option name="Host">Name or IP address of the computer the 
    command should be executed on. This host must be in the list of known hosts
    (see SSH2 preference page).
    </option>       
    <option name="Port">The port number used for the ssh connection. Leave empty
    for the default port no. 22. 
    </option>       
    <option name="Timeout">Enter the number of seconds after any try to connect 
    should time out. Leave empty for the default of 50 seconds.
    </option>       
    <option name="Username">Specify the user name for the ssh connection. Leave
    empty for the current user.
    </option>
    <option name="Password">Enter the password for the ssh connection. Leave empty
    if you use your private key file or no password is required.
    </option>
    <option name="Passphrase">If your private key file requires a passphrase, enter
    it here.
    </option> 
    <option name="Use known host">The host and its fingerprint have to be known. Further
    configuration can be found in the "SSH2" preference page. If this is unchecked the
    check will be bypassed.
    </option>
    <option name="Check Connection"> Checks if the current configuration can be used to
    open a connection to the host.
    </option>
    <option name="Remote Command">Specify the command that is executed on the
    remote host. It must be found in the remote environment. You can specify 
    arguments (space separated). Use the placeholders &quot;$inFile&quot; and
    &quot;$outFile&quot; for the remote input file and remote output file.
    </option>       
    <option name="Temporary Remote Input File">Specify the name of the file where
    the input data is stored. Specify the full remote path. Not existing 
    directories will be created. The file contains the node's input table as
    comma separated values, with column headers and row IDs in the first column.
    The file is deleted after execution.   
    </option>       
    <option name="Temporary Remote Output File">Specify the name of the file where
    the remote command writes the output data to. Specify the full remote path. 
    The file must contain the output data as
    comma, tab, or space separated values. The file is deleted after execution.   
    </option>       
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="External Input">Input data for the external tool</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="External Output">Data read from the output file of the tool</outPort>
    </ports>    
</knimeNode>